{
  "reference_number": "2567",
  "clauses": [
    {
      "question": "1. What process should the Government use to set a new emissions reduction target in legislation?",
      "question_index": 0,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "No action should be taken other than what the market decides."
    },
    {
      "question": "2. If the Government sets a 2050 target now, which is the best target for New Zealand?",
      "question_index": 1,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "If our government insists on going down this fraudulent path, it must make as little change to the status quo as possible."
    },
    {
      "question": "3. How should New Zealand meet its targets?",
      "question_index": 2,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "We produce less than one per cent of global emmisions. Any action is nothing but vanity on the part of our government at the\n expense of our neediest people."
    },
    {
      "question": "4. Should the Zero Carbon Bill allow the 2050 target to be revised if circumstances change?",
      "question_index": 3,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "The science needs to be uncorrupted by an independant examination of the IPCC and the political structures that fund climate\n\n research around the world. The IPCC is corrupt and we should not be taxed or regulated because of what this discredited group\n says."
    },
    {
      "question": "5. The Government proposes that three emissions budgets of five years each (i.e. covering the next 15 years) be in place at any given time. Do you agree with this proposal?",
      "question_index": 15,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "6. Should the Government be able to alter the last emissions budget (i.e. furthest into the future)?",
      "question_index": 4,
      "answer": "Yes - each incoming Government should have the option to review the third budget in the sequence",
      "answer_index": 14,
      "notes": "We must have the ability to roll back the power of an unelected regulatory organisation in the future."
    },
    {
      "question": "7. Should the Government have the ability to review and adjust the second emissions budget within a specific range under exceptional circumstances? See p36 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 5,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "We must have the ability to roll back the power of an unelected regulatory organisation in the future."
    },
    {
      "question": "8. Do you agree with the considerations we propose that the Government and the Climate Change Commission take into account when advising on and setting budgets? See p44 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 6,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": "Despite an overwhelming lack of evidence of any human caused climate change, we citizens are being railroaded into accepting a lie."
    },
    {
      "question": "9. Should the Zero Carbon Bill require Governments to set out plans within a certain timeframe to achieve the emissions budgets?",
      "question_index": 7,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": "The less regulation the government get to do to me, the better."
    },
    {
      "question": "10. What are the most important issues for the Government to consider in setting plans to meet budgets? For example, who do we need to work with, what else needs to be considered?",
      "question_index": 8,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "Stop perpetuating the lie that the scientific community has reached consensus. It has not. Just ignoring or silenceing those who\ndisagree does not make for consensus. Government needs to be honest and represent the truth and the will of voters, not cow-tow\n\nto the United Nations, greenpeace or any other non elected entity."
    },
    {
      "question": "11. The Government has proposed that the Climate Change Commission advises on and monitors New Zealand's progress towards its goals. Do you agree with these functions? See p42 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 9,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": "Thats putting the fox in cahrge of the hen house."
    },
    {
      "question": "12. What role do you think the Climate Change Commission should have in relation to the New Zealand Emissions Trading Scheme (NZ ETS)?",
      "question_index": 10,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "None at all."
    },
    {
      "question": "13. The Government has proposed that Climate Change Commissioners need to have a range of essential and desirable expertise. Do you agree with the proposed expertise? See p45 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 11,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": "A climate change commision should not exist."
    },
    {
      "question": "14. Do you think the Zero Carbon Bill should cover adapting to climate change?",
      "question_index": 12,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": "Individuals should adapt, not by decree but by natural need."
    },
    {
      "question": "15. The Government has proposed a number of new functions to help us adapt to climate change. Do you agree with the proposed functions? See p47 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 13,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "16. Should we explore setting up a targeted adaptation reporting power that could see some organisations share information on their exposure to climate change risks?",
      "question_index": 14,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "Do you have any other comments you'd like to make?",
      "question_index": 16,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "Just as Kyoto proved to be a scam, so too is the Paris Accord. How many time does the bias of the IPCC and the environmental media\n\nneed to be exposed before this stops? How many more doomsday models need to be proven far from perceptive before this stops.\nThe establishment of a Climate Czar will do nothing to mitigate climate change. Climate change has always happened and always will.\n\nNo scientist can accurately measure the amount of effect people have on the atmosphere. Theories fed to us are always speculative,\ndrastic and innacurate. This proposition will have a negative effect on the people of New Zealnd. Most of all on the poor, and for what?\n\nA bumch of unfounded predictions made by corrupt scientists propogated by a biased media and enforced by a tyrannical\ngovernment. F off with this bollocks."
    }
  ]
}
